Zhe Gan

Microsoft Building 112, Phone: Provided upon request 14865 NE 36th St, Email: zhe.gan@microsoft.com
Redmond, WA 98052 Homepage: http://zhegan27.github.io/

Research Interests

I am an NLP Scientist at Microsoft Business AI and Research, primarily working on dialogue, machine reading comprehension (MRC), and natural language generation (NLG). I also have broad interests on various machine learning and NLP topics.

Education

• Duke University, Durham, NC

Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering

09/2013 - 03/2018

Peking University, Beijing, China

M.S., Electrical Engineering B.S., Electrical Engineering 09/2010 - 07/2013

09/2006 - 07/2010

Experience

• Microsoft Business AI and Research

04/2018 - present

NLP Scientist.

Dialogue, machine reading comprehension (MRC), and natural language generation (NLG)

• Information Initiative at Duke (iiD)

09/2013 - 03/2018

Research Assistant, Advisor: Prof. Lawrence Carin

- (*i*) Deep Bayesian Learning: developing deep generative models for computer vision and natural language processing applications, including VAE and GAN
- (ii) Bayesan Deep Learning: designing stochastic gradient variational inference algorithms and stochastic gradient MCMC methods for scalable Bayesian inference

• Microsoft Research Redmond

05/2017 - 08/2017

Research Intern. Advisor: Xiaodong He, Lihong Li, Ph.D

Deep reinforcement learning for vision and language intelligence, with focus on the visual storytelling task.

• Microsoft Research Redmond

05/2016 - 08/2016

Research Intern. Advisor: Xiaodong He, Jianfeng Gao, Li Deng, Ph.D

- (i) image captioning: using deep learning techniques to improve the state-of-the-art of image and video captioning.
- (ii) deep conflation: using deep learning techniques to implement conflation for business data analytics.

• Adobe Research

06/2015 - 09/2015

Data Scientist Intern. Advisor: Hung Bui, Ph.D

Recurrent neural networks (RNN) for NLP applications, including sentence classification, sentence retrieval and sentence generation

Publications

Arxiv

- 1. Q. Huang*, **Z. Gan***, A. Celikyilmaz, D. Wu, J. Wang and X. He "Hierarchically Structured Reinforcement Learning for Topically Coherent Visual Story Generation", *arXiv* preprint arXiv:1805.08191
- 2. X. Zhang, R. Henao, **Z. Gan**, Y. Li and L. Carin "Multi-Label Learning from Medical Plain Text with Convolutional Residual Models", arXiv preprint arXiv:1801.05062

Referred Conference

- 1. Y. Pu, S. Dai, **Z. Gan**, W. Wang, G. Wang, Y. Zhang, R. Henao and L. Carin "Multi-Domain Joint Distribution Learning with Generative Adversarial Nets", *Int. Conf. Machine Learning* (ICML), 2018
- 2. T. Xu, P. Zhang, Q. Huang, H. Zhang, Z. Gan, X. Huang and X. He "AttnGAN: Fine-Grained Text to Image Generation with Attentional Generative Adversarial Networks", Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018
- 3. W. Wang, Z. Gan, W. Wang, D. Shen, J. Huang, W. Ping, S. Satheesh and L. Carin "Topic Compositional Neural Language Model", *Artificial Intelligence and Statistics* (AISTATS), 2018
- 4. Y. Pu, M. R. Min, **Z. Gan** and L. Carin "Adaptive Feature Abstraction for Translating Video to Text", *Proc. American Association of Artificial Intelligence* (**AAAI**), 2018
- 5. **Z. Gan**, L. Chen, W. Wang, Y. Pu, Y. Zhang, H. Liu, C. Li and L. Carin "Triangle Generative Adversarial Networks", *Neural Information Processing Systems* (NIPS), 2017
- 6. Y. Pu, W. Wang, R. Henao, L. Chen, **Z. Gan**, C. Li, and L. Carin "Adversarial Symmetric Variational Autoencoder", *Neural Information Processing Systems* (NIPS), 2017
- 7. Y. Pu, **Z. Gan**, R. Henao, C. Li, S. Han and L. Carin "VAE Learning via Stein Variational Gradient Descent", *Neural Information Processing Systems* (**NIPS**), 2017
- 8. Y. Zhang, D. Shen, G. Wang, **Z. Gan**, R. Henao and L. Carin "Deconvolutional Paragraph Representation Learning", *Neural Information Processing Systems* (**NIPS**), 2017
- 9. **Z. Gan**, Y. Pu, R. Henao, C. Li, X. He and L. Carin "Learning Generic Sentence Representations Using Convolutional Neural Networks", *Conf. on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing* (EMNLP), 2017 Oral
- 10. Y. Zhang, **Z. Gan**, K. Fan, Z. Chen, R. Henao, D. Shen and L. Carin "Adversarial Feature Matching for Text Generation", *Int. Conf. Machine Learning* (**ICML**), 2017
- 11. Y. Zhang, C. Chen, **Z. Gan**, R. Henao and L. Carin "Stochastic Gradient Monomial Gamma Sampler", *Int. Conf. Machine Learning* (ICML), 2017
- 12. **Z. Gan**, C. Li, C. Chen, Y. Pu, Q. Su and L. Carin "Scalable Bayesian Learning of Recurrent Neural Networks for Language Modeling", Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2017 Oral
- 13. **Z. Gan**, C. Gan, X. He, Y. Pu, K. Tran, J. Gao, L. Carin and L. Deng "Semantic Compositional Networks for Visual Captioning", *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR), 2017 Spotlight
- 14. C. Gan, **Z. Gan**, X. He, J. Gao and L. Deng "StyleNet: Generating Attractive Visual Captions with Styles", Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2017
- 15. **Z. Gan**, P. D. Singh, A. Joshi, X. He, J. Chen, J. Gao and L. Deng "Character-level Deep Conflation for Business Data Analytics", *Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), 2017
- 16. Y. Xian, Y. Pu, **Z. Gan**, L. Lu and A. Thompson "Adaptive DCTNet for Audio Signal Classification", *Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), 2017
- 17. Q. Su, X. Liao, C. Li, **Z. Gan** and L. Carin "Unsupervised Learning with Truncated Gaussian Graphical Models", *Proc. American Association of Artificial Intelligence* (**AAAI**), 2017 Oral
- 18. Y. Zhang, Z. Gan and L. Carin "Generating Text via Adversarial Training", NIPS Workshop, 2016
- 19. Y. Xian, Y. Pu, **Z. Gan**, L. Lu and A. Thompson "Modified DCTNet for Audio Signals Classification", *Journal of the Acoustical Society of America*, 2016

- 20. Y. Pu, **Z. Gan**, R. Henao, X. Yuan, C. Li, A. Stevens and L. Carin "Variational Autoencoder for Deep Learning of Images, Labels and Captions", *Neural Information Processing Systems* (NIPS), 2016
- 21. J. Song, **Z. Gan** and L. Carin "Factored Temporal Sigmoid Belief Networks for Sequence Learning", *Int. Conf. Machine Learning* (**ICML**), 2016
- 22. C. Li, A. Stevens, C. Chen, Y. Pu, **Z. Gan** and L. Carin "Learning Weight Uncertainty with Stochastic Gradient MCMC for Shape Classification", *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR), 2016 Spotlight
- 23. C. Chen, D. Carlson, **Z. Gan**, C. Li and L. Carin "Bridging the Gap Between Stochastic Gradient MCMC and Stochastic Optimization", *Artificial Intelligence and Statistics* (**AISTATS**), 2016 Oral
- 24. **Z. Gan**, C. Li, R. Henao, D. Carlson and L. Carin "Deep Temporal Sigmoid Belief Networks for Sequence Modeling", *Neural Information Processing Systems* (**NIPS**), 2015
- 25. R. Henao, **Z. Gan**, J. Lu and L. Carin "Deep Poisson Factor Modeling", Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS), 2015
- 26. **Z. Gan**, C. Chen, R. Henao, D. Carlson and L. Carin "Scalable Deep Poisson Factor Analysis for Topic Modeling", *Int. Conf. Machine Learning* (ICML), 2015
- 27. **Z. Gan**, R. Henao, D. Carlson and L. Carin "Learning Deep Sigmoid Belief Networks with Data Augmentation", *Artificial Intelligence and Statistics* (AISTATS), 2015

Book Chapter

1. **Z. Gan**, X. Yuan, R. Henao, E. Tsalik and L. Carin "Inference of Gene Networks Associated with the Host Response to Infectious Disease", Chapter 13 of Book *Big Data Over Networks*. Cambridge University Press. In Press.

PhD Dissertation

1. **Z. Gan** "Deep Generative Models for Vision and Language Intelligence", Duke University.

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

09/2014-12/2014

STA 601 - Bayesian and Modern Statistics

Instructor: David Dunson, Ph.D

Teaching Assistant

01/2015-05/2015

ECE 587 - Information Theory Instructor: Ahmad Beirami, Ph.D

Professional Activities

Journal Reviewer: Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering, IET Computer Vision

Conference Reviewer: NIPS 2018/2016, CVPR 2018, EMNLP 2018, AAAI 2016, IJCAI 2016, UAI 2016/2015

Talks

- "Deep Generative Models for Vision and Language Intelligence", Ph.D. Final Defense, Durham, NC, February 2018
- "Deep Generative Models for Vision and Language Intelligence", IBM Thomas J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown, NY, October 2017
- "Deep Generative Models for Vision and Language Intelligence", NVIDIA, Santa Clara, CA, September 2017
- "Deep Generative Models for Vision and Language Intelligence", Apple, Cupertino, CA, September 2017
- "Learning Generic Sentence Representations Using Convolutional Neural Networks", *EMNLP*, Copenhagen, Denmark, September 2017

- "Semantic Compositional Networks for Visual Captioning", CVPR, Hawaii, July 2017
- "Semantic Compositional Networks for Visual Captioning", *Ph.D. Preliminary Exam*, Durham, NC, April 2017
- "Deep Generative Models for Sequence Learning", Ph.D. Qualifying Exam, Durham, NC, December 2015

Software Skills

Python (Theano, Tensorflow), Matlab, R and C

Awards

ECE Fellowship, Duke University, 2013 National Scholarship, Department of Minister of Education of China, 2010-2013.

Graduate Coursework

Bayesian and Modern Statistics, Probabilistic Machine Learning, Advanced Machine Learning, Statistical Inference, Statistical Computation, Information Theory, Graphical Models & Inference, Optimization For Engineers